Finding Aid for National Archive on Sino-American Relations records, 1971-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
National Archive on Sino-American Relations records 1971-1984
National Archive on Sino-American Relations.
1 oversize folders
28 linear feet
87260 Bimu C539 2; Bimu C539 Outsize
Grant project of the Center for Chinese Studies of the University of Michigan to locate and collect materials of visitors to the Peoples Republic of China since the reopening of diplomatic contact in 1971. Printed and manuscript diaries and journals, recollections, reports, correspondence, and audio-tapes; oral interviews with members of the United States Table Tennis Association team; and administrative files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred from the University of Michigan Center for Chinese Studies which was home to the National Archive project (donor no. 6670 ). The records were received in 1981 and 1985.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research except for a few indicated files. Other materials (as indicated) may not be published or quoted from without the permission of the document creator.
The University of Michigan National Archive on Sino-American Relations is a comprehensive historical collection documenting the informal relations between China and the United States from 1971 through 1980. Established in July 1977 through a grant from of the Henry Luce Foundation, the Sino-American Archive was a product of the vision of two University of Michigan professors: the late Alexander Eckstein, professor of economics, and the late Michel Oksenberg, professor of political science. During its formative years, the Archive benefited greatly from the support of Albert Feuerwerker, professor of history and director of the Center for Chinese Studies at the University of Michigan, and of Allen Whiting, professor of political science at the University of Michigan.
The Archive was established to collect two types of documentation. The first consisted of diaries, reports, notes, memoranda, and other written materials of select Americans who visited China, 1971-80. The second included oral history tapes and transcripts on the reciprocal table tennis visits in 1971 and 1972 and tapes and notes from the visit to China of the Philadelphia Orchestra.
In developing the archive, the project leaders knew that it would not be possible or desirable to locate and contact all of the tens of thousands of Americans who traveled to China from 1971-80. The Archive stressed the acquisition and preservation of unique or nearly unique research materials from individuals who participated in two kinds of exchanges: (1) government facilitated exchanges sponsored by the Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China, the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations and the U.S.-China Trade Council; and (2) ad hoc visits of groups of eminent scientists, businessmen, journalists, scholars, civic leaders and others. The Archive also contacted prominent Americans who traveled to China independently, rather than as members of groups organized by profession or interest. Individuals were contacted, however, not simply because they had traveled to China, but because they had special training, expertise or interests which enabled them to offer unique insights into Chinese society and politics and into Sino-American relations.
Once identified, the individuals were encouraged to deposit their original documents in the National Archive or other such repository where they would be available for research use. Because of the topical nature of these materials and the danger than many of them would be lost, the Archive departed somewhat from standard archival practice and agreed to accept photocopies.
This record group consists of the following series: Americans in China, 1971-1980; Oral interviews, transcripts, and other sound recordings; Administrative and Background files; and Visual materials.
The bulk of the record group is the Americans in China series, which is arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual or group visiting China. As part of the grant, the project head created a detailed subject guide to the contents of the files. This 313 page guide, entitled Americans in China 1971-1980; a guide to the University of Michigan National Archive on Sino-American Relations is available at the Bentley Historical Library and at several other college and university libraries. The following is a list of the subject arrangement of the guide.
Acupuncture
Agriculture
Archaeology
Architecture
Art
Childcare
Chinese Communist Party
Chinese Visitors to the United States
Cities
Communes
Cultural Revolution
Customs
Economics
Education
Environment
Family Life
Festivals
Foreign Policy
Health Care
History
Industry
Interviews and Meetings
Legal System
Libraries and Archives
Lifestyle
Linguistics
Literature
Mass Media
Medical Science
Military
Minorities
Museums
Performing Arts
Political and Social Organization
Politics
Population Planning
Provinces and Autonomous Regions
Publications
Religion
Science and Technology
Sports
Trade
Transportation
United States-China Relations
Universities and Institutes
Women
Subjects:
China--History--1949-; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States Table Tennis Association.; University of Michigan. Center for Chinese Studies.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
China--History--1949-; University of Michigan. Center for Chinese Studies.
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Videotapes.
- Americans in China 1971-1980
  - Abourezk, Sen. James (Box 1)
    (slides in box 25)
  - Abrams, Dr. Arnold (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Herbert K. (Box 1)
  - Achorn, Robert C. (Box 1)
  - Adkisson, Perry L. (Box 1)
  - Aliferis, James (Boston Symphony Orchestra) (Box 1)
  - Allen, Steve (Box 1)
    (photographs in box 25)
  - Almquist, Johan (Box 1)
  - Ambler, Ernest (Box 1)
  - American Cancer Society Delegation (Box 1)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 1)
  - American Herbal Pharmacology Delegation (Box 1)
  - American Medical Association Delegation, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - American Plant Studies Delegation (Box 1)
  - American Schistosomiasis Delegation (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Thomas J. (Box 1)
  - Anderson, W.S. (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Mark (Box 1)
  - Anrig, Gregory R. (Box 1)
  - Arena, Jay M. (Box 1)
  - Ariyoshi, George R. (Box 1)
  - Ashley, Thomas L. (Box 1)
  - Asper, Samuel P. (Box 1)
  - Atlas, David (Box 1)
  - Attwood, William (Box 1)
  - AuCoin, Les (Box 1)
  - Australian Cultural Mission (Box 1)
  - Australian National University (Box 1)
  - Avaikian, Avak (Box 1)
  - Ayers, Thomas G. (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Margaret (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Charles L. (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Stephen (Box 1)
  - Barber, Sue (Box 1)
  - Bardeen, John (Box 1)
  - Battat, Joseph Y. (Box 1)
  - Batten, Frank (Box 1)
  - Batten, William M. (Box 1)
  - Baum, Margaret H. (Box 1)
    (no quotations permitted without donor's permission)
  - Beaton, Roderick W. (Box 2)
  - Becker, Jerry P. (Box 2)
  - Belgum, David (Box 2)
  - Bell, Derrick (Box 2)
  - Bemiss, Fitzgerald (Box 2)
  - Bender, Marilyn (Box 2)
  - Bennett, Charles (Box 2)
  - Benton, Marjorie (Box 2)
  - Berliner, Joseph S. (Box 2)
  - Bigby, Paul S. (Box 2)
    (audio-tapes in box 21)
  - Birch, Cyril (Box 2)
  - Black, Creed (Box 2)
  - Blanchard, Juliet S. (Box 2)
  - Block, William (Box 2)
  - Blumberg, Richard W. (Box 2)
  - Boggan, Tim, 4 folders (Box 2)
    (literary rights retained by donor)
  - Bonner, James (Box 2)
  - Bonilla, Manuel G. (Box 2)
  - Bookman, Ron (Box 2)
  - Bowen, William G. (Box 2)
  - Bragg, John (Box 2)
  - Brandow, George E. (Box 2)
  - Branscomb, Lewis M., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Bregman, David (Box 2)
  - Brennan, Donald G. (Box 2)
    (restrictions on publication of materials)
  - Brenner, Alfred E. (Box 2)
  - Brown, Robert & Betty (Box 2)
  - Browne, Millard C. (Box 2)
    (slide presentation in box 25; cassette of slide presentation in box 21)
  - Bruce, John I. (Box 2)
  - Bryan, J. Stewart (Box 2)
  - Buben, George, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Buchman, Mark E. (Box 2)
  - Bugliarello, George (Box 2)
  - Bullock, Mary (Box 2)
  - Bumpers, Dale (Box 2)
  - Buncke, Harry J. (Box 2)
  - Burke, Fred G. (Box 2)
  - Burn, Barbara (Box 2)
  - Burnham, Donald C. (Box 2)
    (see also three films in box 27)
  - Busch, Robert H. (Box 2)
  - Butler, Steve (Box 2)
    (see audiocassette in box 21)
  - Byle, Arvon D. (Box 2)
  - Cahill, James, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Calhoun, Daniel (Box 3)
  - Camp, Sharon L. (Box 3)
  - Carey, Freeman H., 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Carey, William (Box 3)
  - Casarett, Alison P. (Box 3)
  - Casey, Kenneth L. (Box 3)
    (videocassette in box 27)
  - Castleton, Kenneth (Box 3)
  - Cawthorne, Dennis O. (Box 3)
  - Champeau, Harold (Box 3)
  - Chang, Min-Chueh (Box 3)
  - Chang, Parris (Box 3)
  - Chao, Edward C. T. (Box 3)
  - Chao, Yuen Ren (Box 3)
  - Chapman, James L. (Box 3)
  - Chen, Lillian (Box 3)
  - Chen, Nai-ruenn (Box 3)
  - Cheng, Yvonne (Box 3)
  - Chiang, H.C. (Box 3)
  - Childers, Norman F. (Box 3)
  - "China in Transition" (Box 3)
  - Chollar, Robert, 2 folders (Box 3)
    (audio-tapes in box 21; slides in box 26)
  - Chu, Samuel (Box 4)
  - Clark, Robert (Box 4)
  - Clarke, William (Box 4)
  - Clendinen, James A. (Box 4)
  - Cleveland, Harlan (Box 4)
  - Cobb, W. Montague (Box 4)
  - Cockrell, Lila (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Daniel M. (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Jerome A. (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Paul (Box 4)
  - Colman, John E. (Box 4)
  - Conley, Charles (Box 4)
  - Congresswomen's Delegation (Box 4)
  - Conte, Silvio O. (Box 4)
  - Cony, Edward (Box 4)
  - Cook, R. James (Box 4)
  - Cook, Stanton (Box 4)
    (see also oversize folder)
  - Corliss, John O. (Box 4)
  - Cornell, Julien (Box 4)
  - Coulson, Jack R. (Box 4)
  - Cranston, Alan (Box 4)
  - Crim, Alonzo A. (Box 4)
  - Crockett, George (Box 4)
  - Cummings, Martin (Box 4)
  - Cunningham, Richard G. (Box 4)
  - Dahlby, Tracy (Box 4)
  - Dantzig, George (Box 4)
  - Dauer, William E. (Box 4)
  - Davis, Stanley N. (Box 4)
  - Day, Robert (Box 4)
  - DeBakey, Michael E. (Box 4)
  - Debre, Francois (Box 4)
  - Deck, Arthur C. (Box 4)
  - Dedmon, Emmett (Box 4)
  - Dellinger, Dave (Box 4)
  - Denny, David (Box 4)
  - DeVries, Donald L., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Diamond, Richard M. (Box 4)
  - Dimond, E. Grey (Box 4)
  - Donnithorne, Audrey, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Dull, Jack L., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Dupree, Louis (Box 5)
  - Du Temple, Octave (Box 5)
  - Eames, W.R. (Box 5)
  - Early, Bert H. (Box 5)
  - Eastman, Lloyd E. (Box 5)
  - Ebert, James D. (Box 5)
  - Eckstein, Alexander (Box 5)
  - Edwards, Jack, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Edwards, Vee (Box 5)
  - Effler, Donald B. (Box 5)
  - Eisen, Fred H. (Box 5)
  - Elzinga, Aant (Box 5)
  - Emanuel, Irvin (Box 5)
  - Emery, Kenneth (Box 5)
  - Enarson, Harold (Box 5)
  - Enderton, Catherine (Box 5)
  - Engelhardt, H. Tristram (Box 5)
  - Ensminger, M.E. and Audrey, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Eskew, Rhea T. (Box 5)
  - Erck, Martin N. (Box 5)
  - Fadeley, Nancie (Box 5)
  - FAO Proposals and Reviews (Box 5)
  - Feuerwerker, Albert, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Feuerwerker, Albert, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Fill, Dennis (Box 6)
  - Fincher, Beverly (Box 6)
  - Findley, Paul (Box 6)
  - Fingar, Thomas (Prof) (Box 6)
  - First Friendship Delegation of American Radical Political Economists (Box 6)
  - Fitt, Alfred B. -- Lois Rice (wife) (Box 6)
  - Flory, Paul J., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Fong, Hiram L. (Box 6)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (Box 6)
  - Fox, Renee C. (Box 6)
  - Freehling, Joan S. (Box 6)
  - Freehling, Stanley (Box 6)
  - Fretwell, Elbert K. Jr. (Box 6)
  - Friberg, J.B. (Box 6)
  - Friend, Theodore (Box 6)
  - Frolic, B. Michael (Box 6)
  - Fuller, Kit (Box 6)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 6)
  - Gale, Robert Peter (Box 6)
  - Galston, Arthur (Box 6)
  - Gardner, John W. (Box 6)
  - Garwin, Richard L., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Geisert, Gene A. (Box 6)
  - Gerstley, James M. (Box 6)
  - Giancarlo, Gene (Box 6)
  - Ginsberg, Ruth B. (Box 6)
  - Ginsberg, Spring (Box 6)
  - Glassman, Joel (Box 6)
  - Gleicher, Morris (Box 6)
  - Goldman, Merle (Box 6)
  - Gorman, Edward (Box 6)
  - Gould, Anne & Dick (Box 6)
  - Granich, Max (Box 6)
  - Grant, James P. (Box 6)
  - Grant, Richard E. (Box 6)
  - Gray, John D. (Box 6)
  - Green, Paul E. (Box 6)
  - Guerrant, Mona (Box 7)
  - Guralnick, Walter (Box 7)
  - Haber, Mrs. William (Box 7)
  - Hadden, Frances and Richard (Box 7)
  - Hall, Carl W., 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Hamlin, Joyce (Box 7)
  - Harlan, Jack R. (Box 7)
  - Harrison, J. Rufford (Box 7)
    (also in outsize folder)
  - Hart, Gary (Box 7)
    (cassette tape in box 21)
  - Harwood, Richard R. (Box 7)
  - Hauge, Gabriel (Box 7)
  - Hay, Allan (Box 7)
  - Hays, Howard (Box 7)
    (photographs in box 26)
  - Henning, Harold (Box 7)
  - Herbert, Victor (Box 7)
    (slides in box 26)
  - Hesburgh, Theodore (Box 7)
  - Hewitt, William A., 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Heyns, Roger W. (Box 7)
  - Hiatt, Howard H. (Box 7)
  - Ho, Ping-ti (Box 7)
  - Hoffman, Robert (Box 7)
  - Holton, Percy G. (Box 7)
  - Hornby, William H. (Box 7)
  - Host, Margaret Ayers, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Howard, Joseph (Box 7)
  - Hsu, Kai-yu (Box 7)
    (Not to be quoted with identification of author or of any of the persons involved)
    (also photos in box 26)
  - Hsueh, Chun-Tu (Box 7)
  - Huang, Philip (Box 7)
  - Huang, Su-Shu (Box 7)
    (also slides in box 26)
  - Hucker, Charles O. (Box 7)
  - Hughes, Harry R. (Box 7)
  - Hughes, John (Box 7)
  - Hunt, James B. (Box 7)
  - Huson, F.R. (Box 7)
  - Ibele, Warren (Box 7)
  - Ichord, Richard H. (Box 7)
  - Jack, Mr. & Mrs. Homer A. (Box 7)
  - Jaffe, Frederick (Box 7)
  - Janey, Jane, 2 folders (Box 7)
    (slides and photographs in box 26)
  - Jang, John (Box 7)
  - Javits, Jacob K. (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Kay (Box 7)
  - Jurney, Dorothy (Box 7)
    (cassette tapes in box 21)
  - Kagan, Leigh (Box 7)
  - Kallgren, Joyce (Box 8)
  - Kampelman, Max (Box 8)
  - Kantrowitz, Arthur (Box 8)
  - Katz, Arnold M. (Box 8)
  - Keatley, Anne (Box 8)
  - Keely, Ann (Box 8)
  - Kellogg, William W. (Box 8)
  - Kelman, Arthur (Box 8)
  - Kenney, Kathy (Box 8)
  - Kessen, William (Box 8)
  - Kiernan, Owen B. (Box 8)
  - Kirkby, Richard (Box 8)
    (notes not to be cited or quoted without permission)
  - Kirkpatrick, Clayton (Box 8)
  - Kisslinger, Carl (Box 8)
  - Kleinman, Arthur (Box 8)
  - Knowles, John (Box 8)
  - Knowlton, Winthrop (Box 8)
  - Knuth, Donald & Jill (Box 8)
  - Koppelman, Julius (Box 8)
  - Kridl, Andrew G. (Box 8)
  - Kroutil, Wayne (Box 8)
  - Kuhn, Philip (Box 8)
  - Kuo, Thomas C. (Box 8)
  - Lacy, Dan (Box 8)
  - Laing, Ellen (Box 8)
    (no quotations permitted without author's permission)
  - Lamm, R.D. (Box 8)
  - Lantz, Everett D. (Box 8)
  - Lau, Lawrence J. (Box 8)
  - Laventhol, David (Box 8)
  - Leaf, Alexander (Box 8)
  - Leclerc de Sablons, Jean (Box 8)
  - Lee, Lieng-Huang (Box 8)
  - Lee, Mathew H.M., 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Lee, Philip R. (Box 8)
  - Leonard-Barton, Dorothy (Box 8)
  - Leontief, Wassily (Box 8)
  - Lenchuk, Paul (Box 8)
  - Leone, Louis A. (Box 8)
  - Lepp, Gerald P. (Box 8)
  - Lesher, Richard L. (Box 8)
  - Levine, Herbert J. (Box 8)
  - Levitt, Norma U. (Box 8)
  - Li, Choh-Luh (Box 8)
  - Li, Frederick P. (Box 8)
  - Li, Victor, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Lieberthal, Kenneth (Box 8)
  - Life in China Interviews (Box 8)
  - Light, Richard L. (Box 8)
  - Light, Timothy (Box 8)
  - Lindbeck, Dr. John R. (Box 8)
  - Lindbom, Theodore R. (Box 9)
  - Loh, Pichon P.Y. (Box 9)
  - Lowe, Mary Johnson (Box 9)
  - Lowrance, John (Box 9)
  - Lubkin, Gloria B. (Box 9)
  - Lyman, Richard (Box 9)
  - Ma, Laurence (Box 9)
  - MacDonald, Peter (Box 9)
  - MacKenzie, James (Box 9)
  - MacLaury, Bruce K. (Box 9)
  - Magnuson, Warren (Box 9)
  - Maher, Laurence J. (Box 9)
  - Major, John S., 2 folders (Box 9)
    (not to be quoted without permission)
  - Malde, Harold E. (Box 9)
  - Malt, Ronald (Box 9)
  - Mann, Marion (Box 9)
  - Mansfield, Mike (Box 9)
  - Maren, Thomas H. (Box 9)
  - Mark, Herman (Box 9)
  - Marks, Leonard (Box 9)
  - Martin, Robert R. (Box 9)
  - Mason, I.L. (Box 9)
  - Mather, Richard (Box 9)
  - Mathias, Charles (Box 9)
  - Maurer, Gilbert C. (Box 9)
  - Mayor's Committee Delegation (Box 9)
  - McBride, Stewart D. (Box 9)
  - McClary, Jane (Box 9)
  - McClelland, John Jr. (Box 9)
  - McCloy, John (Box 9)
  - McDermott, Walsh (Box 9)
  - McDowell, Frank (Box 9)
  - McKinney, Ross E. (Box 9)
  - Meacham, Charles H. (Box 9)
  - Mechanic, David (Box 9)
  - Medical Delegation to the People's Republic of China (Box 9)
  - Menzel, Donald (Box 9)
  - Merrifield, D. Bruce (Box 9)
  - Midwest Regional Delegation, US-CPFA (Box 9)
  - Miller, Robert W., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Miller, William F., 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Milliken, William G. (Box 9)
  - Mills, Harriet (Box 9)
  - Mitchell, Joseph S. (Box 10)
    (cassette tape on box 21)
  - Modell, Jerome (Box 10)
  - Moore, Stanford (Box 10)
  - Morawetz, Herbert (Box 10)
  - Morehouse, Ward (Box 10)
  - Morin, Alexander (Box 10)
  - Moser, Robert H. (Box 10)
  - Mosely, W.H. (Box 10)
  - Munk, Walter (Box 10)
  - Murphey, Rhoads, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Murray, Douglas (Box 10)
  - Muskie, Edmund (Box 10)
  - Myers, Ramon, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - National Council for U.S.-China Trade (Box 10)
  - Neal, Stephen (Box 10)
  - Neuman, Robert B. (Box 10)
  - Newman, Leonard (Box 10)
  - Nix, J.R. (Box 10)
  - Noyes, Chris (Box 10)
  - Nunn, Sam, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Oakley, Deborah (Box 10)
  - Odishaw, Hugh (Box 10)
  - Ohio Academy of Sciences, Geographers Delegation (Box 10)
  - Oksenberg, Michel, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Oksenberg, Michel, 8 folders (Box 11)
  - Olds, Glenn A. (Box 11)
  - O'Neill, Michael J. (Box 11)
  - Ostar, Allan W. (Box 11)
  - Overberger, Charles G. (Box 11)
  - Owens, B.D. (Box 11)
  - Oxnam, Robert (Box 11)
  - Panofsky, Wolfgang K.H. (Box 11)
  - Papper, Emanuel, 4 folders (Box 11)
    (slides in box 26; audiocassettes in box 21)
  - Parker, Eugene (Box 11)
  - Parker, Franklin, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Parks, Lyman S. (Box 11)
  - Patrick, Gerald H. (Box 11)
  - Patrick, Hugh (Box 11)
  - Patterson, Eugene (Box 11)
  - People's Law in China (Box 11)
  - Percy, Charles (Box 12)
  - Perrot, Paul, 1 volumes; 1 folders (Box 12)
  - Pettit, George R. (Box 12)
  - Pheney, Mary (Box 12)
  - Picker, Jean (Box 12)
  - Pickowicz, Paul (Box 12)
  - Piel, Gerard (Box 12)
  - Pierpont, W.K. (Box 12)
  - Pifer, Alan (Box 12)
  - Pilkey, Orrin H. (Box 12)
  - Pipes, Richard (Box 12)
  - Plafker, George (Box 12)
  - Pomeranz, Yeshajahu (Box 12)
  - Pope, Lillie & Martin, 4 folders (Box 28)
    (restricted material)
  - Posvar, Wesley W. (Box 12)
  - Power, Sarah and Philip (Box 12)
  - Pribble, Easton (Box 12)
  - Pryor, Mary, 2 folders (Box 12)
    (photos in box 26)
  - Pusey, Nathan M. (Box 12)
  - Quigg, Chris (Box 12)
  - Quinn, John (Box 12)
  - Radke-Yarrow, Marian (Box 12)
  - Rapp, Fred, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Raskas, Bernard S. (Box 12)
  - Rau, Ronald (Box 12)
  - Reed, Richard J. (Box 12)
  - Regan, Donald T. (Box 12)
  - Reinhardt, John E. (Box 12)
  - Reynolds, Bruce (Box 12)
  - Reynolds, Lloyd (Box 12)
  - Reynolds, William (Box 12)
  - Rhodes, James A. (Box 12)
  - Ricker, John (Box 12)
  - Rielly, John E. (Box 13)
  - Risser, Fred (Box 13)
  - Ritchie, Lawrence (Box 13)
  - Robinson, Joan (Box 13)
  - Robinson, Nicholas A. (Box 13)
  - Robinson, Thomas W. (Box 13)
  - Robison, H.E., 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Rockefeller University Delegation (Box 13)
  - Roderick, John (Box 13)
  - Rodgers, Allan (Box 13)
  - Romanowski, Roman R. (Box 13)
  - Rosemond, George P. (Box 13)
  - Rosen, Samuel (Box 13)
  - Rosenthal, Marilyn M. (Box 13)
  - Rosow, Jerome M. (Box 13)
  - Rostow, Eugene V. (Box 13)
  - Roth, Russell (Box 13)
    (see audiocassettes in box 21)
  - Roy, David T. (Box 13)
  - Sachs, Robert G. (Box 13)
  - Saikowski, Charlotte (Box 13)
  - Salmon, Paul B. (Box 13)
  - Salter, Christopher L. (Box 13)
  - Salvaggio, John (Box 13)
  - Samples, R.E. (Box 13)
  - San Francisco Chamber of Commerce, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Saward, Ernest W. (Box 13)
  - Schima, Marilyn (Box 13)
  - Schmidt, Wolfgang (Box 13)
  - Schonberg, Harold (Box 13)
  - Schwartz, Lee (Mrs. Oscar D.) (Box 13)
  - Scott, Hugh (Box 13)
  - Seaborg, Glenn, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Seznec, Alain (Box 13)
  - Shank, Russell (Box 13)
  - Shaplen, Robert (Box 13)
  - Shea, John R. (Box 13)
  - Shirk, Susan (Box 13)
  - Shriver, Sargent (Box 13)
  - Shumacker, Harris B., Jr. (Box 13)
  - Sidel, Victor (Box 13)
  - Sietz, Frederick (Box 13)
  - Signer, Ethan (Box 13)
  - Sivin, Nathan (Box 14)
    (need permission of donor to copy, circulate, or cite)
  - Sixteenth Congressional Delegation (Box 14)
  - Smart, William B. (Box 14)
  - Smith, J. Chandler (Box 14)
  - Smith, Dorothy T. (Box 14)
  - Smith, Stan (Box 14)
  - Snelling, Richard (Box 14)
  - Snyder, Mary-Jane (Box 14)
  - Spain, W.J., Jr. (Box 14)
  - Spencer, Donald C. (Box 14)
  - Spock, Benjamin (Box 14)
  - Staggers, Harley O. (Box 14)
  - Stanley, Margaret, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Steenhoven, Graham (Box 20)
    (not to be published, sold, or quoted verbatim without permission of Mr. Steenhoven)
    (see also three 16mm films in box 27)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (Box 14)
  - Stevenson, H.L. (Box 14)
  - Stone, Jeannette G. (Box 14)
  - Sullivan, John (Box 14)
  - Surrey, Stanley S. (Box 14)
  - Swan, David (Box 14)
  - Sweeris, Connie (Box 14)
  - Sweitzer, James (Box 14)
  - Taeuber, Conrad (Box 14)
  - Tannehill, John (Box 14)
    (see outsize folder)
  - Taylor, Robert L. (Box 14)
  - Temin, Howard M. (Box 14)
  - Temmer, Georges, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Teng, S.Y. (Box 14)
  - Thorhaug, Anitra (Box 14)
  - Ting, Y.C. (Box 14)
  - Tompkins, Ann (Box 14)
  - Townes, Charles H. (Box 14)
  - Townsend, James R. (Box 14)
  - Traiger, Lynn (Box 14)
  - Treadgold, Donald W. (Box 14)
  - Tsuchitani, Patricia, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Tung, Timothy (Box 14)
  - Turgeon, Lynn (Box 14)
  - Umali, D.L. (Box 14)
  - United States Table Tennis Association (Kaminsky), 2 folders (Box 14)
  - United States Table Tennis Association (Kaminsky), 4 folders (Box 15)
  - United States Water Resources Delegation (Box 15)
  - University and College Presidents Delegations (Box 15)
  - University of Michigan Regents Delegation (Box 15)
  - University of Minnesota Delegation (Box 15)
  - Vineyard, Phyllis (Box 15)
  - Viola, Joy W. (Box 15)
  - Walker, William (Box 15)
  - Wallace, Don Jr. (Box 15)
  - Wan, Wei-ying (Box 15)
  - Wareham, Caroline (Box 15)
  - Washington Post (Box 15)
  - Way, E. Leong (Box 15)
  - Webb, Jervis C. (Box 15)
  - Weber, Lillian (Box 15)
  - Wegman, Myron (Box 15)
  - Weigel, Stanley A. (Box 15)
  - Weingartner, Rudolph and Fannia (Box 15)
  - Welch, Norval (Box 15)
  - Welsh, William J. (Box 15)
  - Whalen, Charles (Box 15)
  - Wharton, Dolores and Clifton (Box 15)
  - Wheeler, Thomas L. (Box 15)
  - White, Gilbert (Box 15)
  - White, Paul Dudley (Box 15)
  - White, Robert M., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Whitehurst, William G. (Box 15)
  - Whitehead, Edwin C. (Box 15)
  - Whiting, Allen, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Whitman, Robert (Box 15)
  - Wiesner, Jerome and Laya (Box 15)
  - Wiley, Esther B. (Box 15)
  - Wiley, W. Bradford (Box 15)
  - Williams, Hosea and Juanita (Box 15)
  - Williams, Jack F. (Box 15)
  - Williams, Paul W. (Box 15)
  - Williams, Paul W. (Box 16)
  - Williamson, John H. (Box 16)
  - Wilson, Bob, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Wong, Francis (Box 16)
  - Winship, Thomas (Box 16)
  - Wong, Samuel (Box 16)
  - Woo, Way Dong (Box 16)
  - Wood, Earl H. (Box 16)
  - Woodard, Kim (Box 16)
  - Wortman, Sterling (Box 16)
  - Wu, Ching Sheng (Box 16)
  - Wu, Eugene (Box 16)
  - Wu, Theodore Y. (Box 16)